22 chapter 23 of Black Beauty this LibriVox recording is in the public
domain Black Beauty by Anna suul chapter 23 A Strike for
Liberty One day my lady came down later than usual, and the silk rustled more than
ever. “Drive to the dck of bees she said, and then after a pause, “Are you never
going to get those horses' heads up, York?
Raise him at once and let us have no more of this humoring and
nonsense.” York came to me first, while the groom stood at Ginger's head. He drew my
head back and fixed the rain so tight that it was almost intolerable; then he
went to Ginger, who was impatiently jerking her head up and down against the
bit, as was her way now. She had a good idea idea of what was coming, and the
moment York took the rain off the turret in order to shorten it she took her
opportunity and reared up so suddenly that York had his nose roughly hit and
his hat knocked off; the groom was nearly thrown off his
legs. At once they both flew to her head;
but she was a match for them, and went on plunging, rearing, and kicking in a most
desperate manner. At last she kicked right over the carriage pole and fell
down, after giving me a severe blow on my near quarter. There there is no knowing what
further mischief she might have done had not York promptly sat himself down flat
on her head to prevent her struggling, at the same time calling out, “Unbuckle the
black horse! Run for the winch and unscrew the carriage pole! Cut the trace
here, somebody, if you can't unhitch it!” One of the footmen ran for the winch,
and another brought a knife from the house. The groom soon set me free from
Ginger in the carriage, and led me to my
box. He just turned me in as I was and ran back back to
York. I was much excited by what had happened, and if I had ever been used to
kick or rear I am sure I should have
done it then; but I never had, and there I
stood, angry, sore in my leg, my head still strained up to the turret on the saddle,
and no power to get it down. I was very miserable and felt much inclined to kick
the first person who came near me. Before long, however, Ginger was led in
by two grooms, a good deal knocked about and bruised.
York came with her and gave his orders, and then came to look at me. In a moment
he let down my head. “Confound these check Reigns he said
to himself; “I thought we should have some mischief soon. Master will be sorely
vexed. But there, if a woman's husband can't rule her of course a servant can't;
so I wash my hands of it, and if she can't get to the duchess's garden party
I can't help it.” York did not say this before the men; he always spoke respectfully when they
were by. Now he felt me all over, and soon found the place above my Hawk where I
had been kicked. It was swelled and painful; he ordered it to be sponged with
hot water, and then some lotion was put on. Lord was much put out when he learned
what had happened; he blamed York for giving way to his mistress, to which he
replied that in future he should much prefer to receive his orders only from
his lordship; but I think nothing came of it, for things went on the same as before.
I thought York might have stood up better for his horses, but perhaps I am no
judge. Ginger was never put into the carriage again, but when she was well of
her bruises one of the Lord's younger sons said he would like to have her; he
was sure she would make a good hunter. As for me, I was obliged still to
go in the carriage, and had a fresh partner called Max; he had always been
used to the tight rain I asked him how he bore
it. “Well,” he said, “I bear it because I must;
but it is shortening my life, and it will shorten yours too if you have to stick to
it.” “Do you think,” I said, “that our masters know how bad it is for
us?” “I can't say,” he replied, “but the dealers and the horse doctors know it
very well. I was at a dealers once, who was training me and another horse to go
in as a pair; he was getting our heads up,
as he said, a little higher and a little higher every day. A gentleman who was
there asked him why he did so. 'Because,' said he, 'people won't buy them unless we
do. The London people always want their horses to carry their heads high and to
step high. Of course it is very bad for the horses, but then it is good for trade.
The horses soon wear up, or get diseased, and they come for another
pair.' That,” said Max, “is what he said in my hearing, and you can judge for
yourself.” What I suffered with that rain for four long months in my lady's
carriage it would be hard to describe; but I'm quite sure that, had it lasted
much longer, either my health or my temper would have given
way. Before that, I never knew what it was to foam at the mouth, but now the action
of the sharp bit on my tongue and jaw, and the constrained position of my head
and throat, always caused me to froth at the mouth more or less. Some people think
it very fine to see this, and say, “What fine spirited creatures!” But it is just as unnatural
for horses as for men to foam at the mouth; it is a sure sign of some
discomfort, and should be attended to. Besides this, there was a pressure on
my windpipe, which often made my breathing very uncomfortable; when I
returned from my work my neck and chest were strained and painful, my mouth and
tongue tender, and I felt worn and depressed. In my old home I always knew
that John and my master were my friends; but here, although in many ways I was
well treated, I had no friend. York might have known, and very
likely did know, how that rain harassed me; but I suppose he took it as a matter
of course that it could not be helped; at any rate, nothing was done to relieve
me end of chapter